消灭博士 消灭博士
Exterminate the Doctor! Exterminate the Doctor!
- 消... - 等等
- Exterm... - Wait!
他是Dalek的敌人 他必须被消灭
He is an enemy of the Daleks. He must be exterminated.
他必须先被复制
He must be duplicated first.
请跟Dalek元首联系
Confirm with the Supreme Dalek.
Dalek元首确认了这项命令
Supreme Dalek confirms the order.
我们必须把俘虏 送到复制室
We must take the prisoner to the duplication chamber.
向前走
Proceed.
- 他们很冲动 不是吗 - 他们会杀了任何人
- Impulsive, aren't they? - They'd kill anybody,
就算他们需要他
even if they need them.
什么时候轮到你呢
How long before it's your turn
你们要拿要我的复制品干什么
What would do you with my duplicate?
- 那与你无关  - 我觉得有关我可相当喜欢自己
- That does no t concern you.
- Oh, I think it does. I'm rather attached to myself.
你要保持沉默
You will remain silent.
我猜我的脑电波会被传送给Davros
I assume my brain waves are destined for Davros.
你们一定十分需要他
You must need his services very badly.
Dalek是高等种族 我们不需要帮助
Daleks are the superior being. We do not require assistance.
高等 你花了一辈子时间把Tardis引入时间走廊吧
Superior? It took you long enoug to ensnare the Tardis in the Time Corridor.
- 只是一个陷阱 - 嗯 Stien看起来更有效率
- It was but one trap. - Hm. Stien was more effective.
- 一个活生生有思想的人 而不是一部铁锅机器 - 别说了 博士
- A living, thinking being, not some tin-pot machine. - Please, Doctor!
Stien只是一个延伸 Dalek技术的延伸
Stien is but an extension of Dalek technology.
- 什么 - 他是个复制品
- What? - He is a duplicate.
他是 我们基因工程的产物
He is a product of our genetic engineering.
- 你们所有人都是复制品吗 - 是的
- Are you all duplicates? - Yes.
真有意思 我想知道你们本人身上发生了些什么
Interesting. I wonder what happened to the real you.
这很重要 你早点完成你的研究
It is vital you complete your researches as soon as possible.
- 我需要Movellan病毒的样本 - 等一下会拿给你
- I need a sample of the Movellan virus. - It will be brought to you.
我还需要两个Dalek
I will also need two Daleks
来做实验
for experimentation.
那不行
That is forbidden.
如果要我找到解药 我需要活体Dalek组织
If I am to find a cure, I will need living Dalek tissue.
- 我们必须要问过Dalek元首 - 那就去问 快点
- We must consult the Supreme Dalek. - Do so! But be quick!/
自毁系统控制室 被入侵了
The self-destruct chamber has been invaded.
消灭敌人
The hostiles must be exterminated.
没时间了 放弃空间站
There isn't time. Abandon the station.
你应该预料到这个
You should have anticipated this.
最初的计划是救出Davros然后离开
The original plan was to snatch Davros and leave.
不能让Davros有任何危险
Nothing must endanger Davros.
敌人必须被毁掉 必须要服从Dalek
The hostiles must be destroyed. The Daleks must be obeyed!/
外面  关上门  Dalek军队来了
That's outside! Close the door! Dalek troopers!
他们肯定看到我们了 打坏那个摄像头
They must have seen us. Take out that camera.
设个障碍物保护我们
Build a barricade for protection./
- 士兵们已经复制好了吗 - 是的
- Have the soldiers been duplicated? - Yes.
真聪明 告诉我是怎么做的
It's so clever.Do tell me how it's done.
- 不 - 我想你不会的
- No. - Thought you wouldn't.
Tegan怎么办
What about Tegan?
- 她是我们的犯人 - 她不会害人 你们必须放了她
- She is our prisoner. - She's harmless. You must release her.
给他看
Show him.
- 为什么 - 没有同伴的博士
- Why? - A Doctor with no companions
- 看起来一无是处 - 你为什么要这样做
- would be rather incongruous. - Why are you doing this?
你的复制品会回到Gallifrey
Your duplicates will return to Gallifrey.
在我们的控制下, 你要去刺杀 高等议会的成员
At our command, you will assassinate members of the High Council.
不
No!/
我们是被  Dalek元首派来的
We have been sent by the Supreme Dalek.
我们要帮你完成试验
We are to assist in your research.
- 我需要的是Dalek组织,不是帮助 - 你可以从我们身上提取组织
- I need Dalek tissue, not help. - You may remove tissue from us.
很好
Excellent.
我的实验绝不会有害
In no way will my experiment harm.
松开固定锁
Releasing locking clamp.
事实上你们会变得相当精神
In fact, you will become considerably invigorated.
太好了
Perfect.
重新封上你们的铠甲
Reseal your casings.
现在....
Now....
你们服从谁
Who do you obey?
我们服从Davros 他是我们的主人
We obey Davros. He is our Master!
非常好
Excellent.
现在我需要的是Movellan病毒的样本
Now all I require is a sample of the Movellan virus./
命令他们把一个Movellan病毒的样本 从地球上传送过来
Order a cylinder of Movellan virus to be transported from Earth.
遵命
I obey.
把收集器拿给Davros
Take the cylinder to Davros.
非常好
Perfect.
我只有一个请求
I have but one more request.
我希望我们能合作久一点
I require your co-operation a little longer.
一个英勇但是愚蠢的反应 他会制造出一个非常好的奴隶
A spirited but foolish reaction. He will make an excellent slave.
你也会
And so will you./
- 你准备好了吗 - 你这样问好像我有得选一样
- Are you ready? - You ask it as though I have a choice.
每个人都有选...择 这出自宪法 第25次修正版
Everyone has a ch...oice. It's in the C-Constitution, 25th Amendment.
- 你没有上学吗 - 也许我们上的不是同一所学校
- Didn't you go to school? - Maybe we didn't go to the same school.
- 你上的哪所学校 - 我 我不记得了
- Which school did you go to? - I-I c-can't remember.
你记得修正 怎么开始的 我知道那很重要
You remember the Amendments! What was the First? It's important that I know.
告诉我你想起来了
And that you remember.
想想 在你大脑里被关闭的区域寻找
Think! Search the area of your mind that's been shut off.
抵制它 否则就太晚了
Resist before it's too late.
我必须继...续
I must cont...inue.
抵制
Resist!
我必须继...续
I must con...tinue./
(注：Vislor Turlough：S20E03 Mawdryn Undead登场 S21E06 Planet of Fire离开）
（注：Tegan Jovanka：S18E07 Logopolis登场 S21E04 Resurrection of the Daleks离开）
（注：Nyssa：S18E07 Logopolis登场 S20E04 Terminus离开）
（注：Adric S18E03登场 S19E06 Earthshock死亡）
（注： Romana II：S17E01 Destiny of the Daleks重生至第二形态 S18E05 Warriors' Gate被困E空间 在未完成剧集Shada中登场 20周年特别篇：The Five Doctors中采取Shada片段客串）
（注：Romana I：S16E01 The Ribos Operation登场 S17E01 Destiny of the Daleks重生）
（注：K-9 Mark I：S15E02 Invisible Enemy登场 S15E06 The Invasion of Time和Leela留在Gallifrey
K-9 Mark II：S16E01 The Ribos Operation登场 S18E05 Meglos和RomanaII留在E空间 K-9 Mark III出现于衍生剧中 K-9 Mark IV出现于新版第二季 第四季和衍生剧莎拉简大冒险）
（注：Harry Sullivan：S12E01 Robot登场 S13E01 Terror of the Zygons离开）
（注：第四任博士：S12E01 Robot重生后上演换衣秀 S18E07 Logopolis中为阻止法师的阴谋而摔死）
（注：Sarah Jane Smith：S11E01 The Time Warrior登场 S14E02 The Hand of Fear离开 在20周年特别篇：The Five Doctors中客串 在新版中多次客串）
（注：Jo Grant：S08E01：Terror of the Autons登场 S10E05 The Green Death离开）
放松, 博士.不要抵抗 你只会给自己带来...疼痛
Relax, Doctor. Don't fight it. You'll only cause yourself...pain.
（注：Brigadier Alistair Gordon Lethbridge-Stewart：S05E05 The Web of Fear登场 S13E01 Terror of the Zygons离开 在S20E03 Mawdryn Undead 20周年特别篇：The Five Doctors S06E01 Battlefield 三十周年特别篇：Dimensions in Time 莎拉简大冒险：Enemy of the Bane 中均有客串）
（注：Liz Shaw：S07E01 Spearhead from Space登场 S07E04 Inferno离开）
（注：第三任博士：S07E01 Spearhead from Space登场 S11E05 Planet of the Spiders重生）
我-我了解你的感受 疼痛会过去的 放松
I-I know you you feel. The pain will pass. Relax.
快
Quickly!
（注：第三任博士：S07E01 Spearhead from Space登场 S11E05 Planet of the Spiders重生）
背诵修正版
Recite the Amendments!
- 我要尽责 - 你必须要反抗
- I must do my duty. - You must resist.
你要毁了我的大脑
You are destroying my mind./
站到一边
Stand by.
就是它了
That's it.
啊
Aaaagh!/
- 把他们送进时间走廊 - 啊
- Get them into the Time Corridor. - Aaagh!
不... 啊
No...! Aaaaaagh!
跟她一起进去时间走廊
Into the Time Corridor with her.
Dalek已经清理过空间站了 这里是安全的
The Daleks have secured the station. It is safe.
很好
Excellent.
- 博士被抓住了 - 最好别动
- The Doctor has been taken prisoner. - Better still.
马上把他带到我这儿来 快点 我有非常重要的事情要做
He must be brought to me at once. Hurry. There is important work to do.
此刻我已经等了很久了
I have waited a long time for this./
- 你的意思是情况还能更坏点儿  - 是的
- You mean it can get worse? - Yes.
Dalek非常擅长发明痛苦和不体面的死亡方式
The Daleks are very capable of devising painful and undignified ways of dying.
但是还不至于
But not yet.
Dalek需要保持我的脑电波的完整性
The Daleks need my brain waves intact,
一旦消灭了博士
Once the Doctor is exterminated,
不是吗
don't they?
噢...
Oh...!
我就会建立一个新Dalek种族
I shall build a new race of Daleks.
这么轻
It's so light!
他们会更致命
They will be even more deadly!
- 是什么做成的  - 谁知道
- What's it made from? - Who knows?
而我, Davros,
And I, Davros,
会成为它们的领袖
shall be their leader!
它违背了我能想起的所有测试
It defied every test I could think of.
这一次我们会胜出
This time we shall triumph!
我的Dalek会再一次
My Daleks shall once more become
成为高等种族
the Supreme Beings!
它看起来...呃...挺复杂的
It looks...uh...complicated.
试试电脑 电脑里可能有启动顺序
The computer may contain the ignition sequence.
当你启动炸弹 我们是否有必要跟空间站同归于尽
When you've primed your bomb, is it necessary that WE die with the station?
没有人想陪葬  但是有出口吗
None of us want to be martyrs. Know a way out
我提到过的时间走廊 它是存在的 它是真实的 我们可以利用它逃生
The Time Corridor I mentioned. It exists. It's real. We could use it to escape.
- 你觉得怎么样  - 你可以去看看
- What do you think? - You could check it out
在我试着启动这东西的时候
while I try and find a way into this thing.
好的
Right.
你必须合作 必须躺下
You must co-operate. You must lie down.
Davros怎么不在这儿  他应该想看到这一切
Why isn't Davros here? He'd want to see this.
- 他停留在别处 - 这么说来他确实在这儿
- He is otherwise detained. - So he IS here.
这和你无关
It does not concern you.
这次你遇到什么麻烦了
What sort of trouble are you in this time?
好了...
Well...
-不错 -但是它能骗过他们吗
-Not bad. -But would it convince?
如果你看起来不是很生硬...也许可以
If you didn't look too hard... Perhaps.
事实是 你不得不装作看不见
The truth is, you'd have to be blind.
快点
Quickly!
- 你们可以停止假装了 - 你说什么
- You can stop pretending. - What?
- 你们将被送上Dalek的飞船 - Tegan很不舒服
- You will board the Dalek ship. - Tegan is sick.
不用太久了
Not for much longer.
无论如何 我们俩死定了
One way or another, we're both dead.
新纪元开始了
A further recruit.
开始
Initiate.
时间走廊通过气闸
The Time Corridor is through the airlock.
欢迎
Welcome!
- 军队怎么办  - 杀了他们
- What about the troopers? - We kill them.
Dalek呢 我们必须先设好自毁设备
And the Daleks? We must set the self-destruct device first.
谢谢 Zena
Thanks a lot. Zena?
- 我们回去吧 - 不
- We go back. - No!
我们回去
We go back!
- Lt Mercer将进行安全检查 - 那很重要 给他接通无线电
- Lt Mercer will have security clearance. - That's a point. Get him on the radio.
- Dalek能够追踪信号 - 试试高频范围
- The Daleks could trace the signal. - Try a high-frequency range.
- 走吧 - 不 我留在这儿
- Let's go. - No. I should stay.
- 他们会杀了你的 - 不会的 如果你找到了援兵
- They'll kill you. - Not if you get help quickly.
Dalek无法监视所有的
The Daleks can't monitor them all.
必须有人在这儿骗他们久一点
We need someone here to help the deception along.
你是在浪费时间 走吧 快走
You're wasting time. Go. Go!
- 祝你好运 - 你也一样 我会尽快的
- Good luck. - And you. I'll be as quick as I can.
我们可以在墙上打个洞吗
Can we blow a hole in the wall?
可以
Could.
那我们就可以两面夹击了
Then we attack on two fronts.
我的部队在持续增长
My army continues to grow.
有进展了
I'm making progress!
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
戴立克的复兴
校对：NO MORE
翻译：nancydodo
第三部分
本字幕根据知识共享-署名-相同方式共享-4.0国际（CC-BY-SA4.0)协议发布
http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.zh
翻译：nancydodo 校对：NO MORE
后期：小鱼干 监制：于昊源
Turlough
Turlough?
iCelery
军团
Turlough
Turlough!
傻孩子
Foolish boy.
快点儿 我们离开这儿
Quickly! Let's get out of here.
不, 博士
No, Doctor.
真是疯了 Dalek不会因为你抓到我而感谢你的 他们会杀了你
This is madness. The Daleks won't thank you. They'll kill you.
我没有完全讲实话 我服务于Dalek
I didn't quite tell you the truth. I serve the Daleks.
我是它们的特工
I am a Dalek agent.
就是这儿
It's here.
- 这儿没有守卫 - 谢天谢地
- It isn't guarded. - Be grateful.
- 那是什么 - 自毁系统
- What is it? - The self-destruct chamber.
好了 打开它吧
Right. Let's get it open.
- 你们准备做什么 - 你猜
- What are you going to do? - Guess.
- 有人要喝茶吗 - 好
- Would anyone like some tea? - Please.
上校
Colonel?
不用
No.
- 救护车什么时候来 - 不知道
- How long will the ambulance be? - I don't know.
Tegan脑震荡了 她需要医疗照顾
Tegan has severe concussion. She needs medical attention.
有条件时 会有医生照顾她的
She will receive medical attention as soon as it is available.
太感谢了
Thanks very much
真可惜他不想喝茶
Pity he didn't want any tea.
不然他可以睡好几个小时
He'd have slept for hours.
我们就可以从这儿出去了
We've got to get out of here.
我们可以给这些重新接上线吗
Could we rewire these?
我觉得可以
I should think so.
朝前走
Proceed.
- 你什么也做不了 - 我不该留下他们的
- There's nothing you can do. - I left them.
你做的对 现在看你的了
You did the right thing. It's now up to you.
我们必须返回地球.
We have to get back to Earth.
- 他们知道了 - 我们怎么做
- They know. - What do we do?
相信我
Trust me!
Dalek会通知我们
The Daleks will instruct us.
我们来的正是时候
Just in time.
你的迟到给Dalek带来了风险
Your delay put the Dalek plan at risk.
我们胜利了 这就够了
We won. That's all that matters.
空间站 差点儿被摧毁
The space station could have been destroyed.
我要向Dalek元首报告
I must report this to the Supreme Dalek.
- 对不起 我尽力了 - 他们要把我们送到Dalek飞船上
- I'm sorry. I tried. - They're sending us to the Dalek ship.
我已经很不耐烦了
Already I grow impatient.
从哪里开始
Where do we start?
Lytton
Lytton.
Dalek元首在这儿
This is the Supreme Dalek.
现在没啥好失去的了 我该对你们做些什么
Now there's nothing to lose, what can I make of you?
- 我们必须要做点儿什么 - 他们会杀了我们的
- We must do something. - They'll kill us.
- 我必须要做点什么 - 想想
- I have to do something. - Think!
Dalek有飞船,
The Daleks have a ship,
为什么他们要闯进自毁系统控制室 为什么不离开
so why break into the self-destruct chamber? Why not leave?
- 让你的朋友们炸掉他们 - 跟我说
- Let your friends blow themselves up. - Tell me.
因为不管Dalek想要什么 那东西还在这里
Because whatever the Daleks want is still on board.
Davros
Davros!
你可能没办法帮你的朋友 但是你可以杀掉他
You may not be able to help your friends but you could kill HIM.
找找延误的原因
Find out the cause of the delay.
- 我们来晚了 - 他不可能离得很远
- Too late. - He can't be far.
我们可能要花几个小时徒劳的搜寻
We could spend hours searching fruitlessly.
这里满是Dalek
The place is crawling with Daleks.
我必须要找到他... 你要跟我一起来
I have to find him... And you're coming with me.
- 快准备好了 - 犯人有安保
- Nearly ready. - The prisoner is secured.
你必须独自行动  我们被传唤去做其它事情
You must proceed alone. We have been summoned to other duties.
- 不是待到最后 多让人失望呀 - 当你要死的时候,
- Not staying to the bitter end? - When it is time to die,
你会非常痛苦的 要记得跪下来求Dalek
you will, in your agony, beg to pay homage to the Daleks.
你在外面等着
You will wait outside.
他们自视甚高
They take themselves so seriously.
激怒他们只会让你处境更坏
Provoking them only makes it worse for you.
动手吧 我不需要你的同情
Get on with it. I can do without your pity.
你就认为我这样做是因为我喜... 我这样做是因为没有选...选...选择
Do you think I do this because I enj...? That I do this out of ch...ch...choice?
我有...有...有选...选...选择吗
D...D...Do I have a ch...ch...choice?
我没得选
I have no choice.
Davros在用Styles的实验室
Davros is using Styles's laboratory.
我们快做到了
We're nearly there!
我为什么这么激动 这是我最不想做的
Why am I so excited? It's the last thing I'll ever do.
丢了一个收集器
One of the cylinders disappeared!
她去哪儿了 哪儿
Where is she? WHERE?
她走不远的
She won't get far.
啊
Aaaaagh!
喂
Hey!
不
No!
- 他们正分头包抄我们的机械 - 我快弄好了
- They're bypassing the mechanism! - I'm almost there.
你一定不要动这些设备
You must not touch the equipment.
我没有死亡的威胁 你们显得好无力
Without the threat of death, you're quite powerless.
服从
You will obey!
- 激怒Dalek是很不明智的 博士 - 任何反应都会被视为挑衅
- It is unwise to provoke the Daleks Doctor - Any response is deemed provocative.
我知道Dalek已经雄风不在了 还有Davros  我猜他已经是那样了
I know the Daleks of old. And Davros. I assume he's about.
质疑只会引来麻烦
Questions only invite trouble.